<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Ponte d&#x27;Arte, Portugal</title>
    <link href="https://pontedarte.org/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://pontedarte.org" />
    <updated>2019-09-18T01:34:00+02:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Ponte d&#x27;Arte</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://pontedarte.org</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Resiliência Exhibition - Art, Music, Poetry - 2019</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ponte d&#x27;Arte</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://pontedarte.org/resiliencia-exhibition-art-music-poetry-2019.html"/>
        <id>https://pontedarte.org/resiliencia-exhibition-art-music-poetry-2019.html</id>

        <updated>2019-09-18T00:11:36+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://pontedarte.org/media/posts/34/resiliencia_flyer_pontedarte11.jpg" alt="" />
                    On 13 October 2019, we remember the "Resiliência" of living with wildfires in Portugal.
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://pontedarte.org/media/posts/34/resiliencia_flyer_pontedarte11.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>On 13 October 2019, we remember the "Resiliência" of living with wildfires in Portugal.  Join us at Ponte d'Arte, an artist-run organisation in Ponte Da Mucela, to listen to music, be transported by poetry, and experience art experiments.  </p>
<p>Three years ago, due to wildfires worsensed by climate change and a hurricane, we suffered the health and lost lives of people in our region. In the Iberian fire disaster of October 2017, we too lost our posessions to the wildfire, but we decided to go on.  We have rebuilt something bigger and better out of the ashes in Ponte da Mucela, and it is our dream to share it with culture lovers everywhere.<br><br>Wildfires are an ancient and regular problem in Portugal, currently growing due to climate change.  We are motivated by the belief in the healing power of creativity to transform pain.</p>
<p>Our writer in residence, Alfredo J. Ferreiro Salgueiro, will present spoken word poetry.  A group of international art students attending a site-specific art workshop will show their experiments on the theme.  Their mentor on this master class is Prof Kris van 't Hof, from the Royal Academy in Antwerp, Belgium.<br><br>We have a vision for an inspiring and beautiful day and night of remembering. We invite the rural Portuguese-speaking community from the surrounding areas, and the international intellectual and cultural community, to return to this home for creative practice we are building.  We hope to turn the tragedy of the fire into an annual event celebrating resilience through artistic practice, maybe one day an indoor music festival.    </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Contact us</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ponte d&#x27;Arte</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://pontedarte.org/contact-us.html"/>
        <id>https://pontedarte.org/contact-us.html</id>

        <updated>2019-09-16T19:58:29+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://pontedarte.org/media/posts/33/P1050002.jpg" alt="" />
                     Thank you for your interest in Ponte d'Arte. We'd love to&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://pontedarte.org/media/posts/33/P1050002.jpg" alt="" />
                <blockquote>
<p> </p>
<p>Thank you for your interest in Ponte d'Arte.</p>
<p>We'd love to hear from you.<br><br>Regards,</p>
<p><a href="https://pontedarte.org/kris-van-t-hof.html">Kris</a> &amp; <a href="https://pontedarte.org/celia-de-villiers.html">Celia</a></p>
<p> </p>
</blockquote>
<table border="0" width="100%">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td width="20%"> </td>
<td width="60%">
<h2 id="mcetoc_1dktj1pb42">Your message</h2>
</td>
<td width="20%"> </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td bgcolor="white"> </td>
<td bgcolor="olive" width="60%"><form action="https://formspree.io/pontedarte.artsbridge@gmail.com" method="POST">
<p><input name="email" type="email" placeholder="Your email"></p>
<p><textarea cols="40" name="message" rows="10" placeholder="Message"></textarea></p>
<p><button type="submit">SEND</button></p>
</form></td>
<td bgcolor="white">
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Events</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ponte d&#x27;Arte</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://pontedarte.org/events-and-gatherings.html"/>
        <id>https://pontedarte.org/events-and-gatherings.html</id>

        <updated>2019-09-17T23:23:05+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://pontedarte.org/media/posts/32/2019-Instagram-pontedarte-Aug123.jpg" alt="" />
                    The complex is currently undergoing conversion to become a meeting centre with&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://pontedarte.org/media/posts/32/2019-Instagram-pontedarte-Aug123.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>The complex is currently undergoing conversion to become a meeting centre with large and small exhibition spaces, 300m<sup>2</sup> gallery/concert hall, video rooms, a conference room, an art library, studios and workshops, and a small local museum. </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Shared accommodation</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ponte d&#x27;Arte</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://pontedarte.org/shared-accommodation.html"/>
        <id>https://pontedarte.org/shared-accommodation.html</id>

        <updated>2019-09-16T13:52:25+02:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Conimbriga</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ponte d&#x27;Arte</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://pontedarte.org/conimbriga.html"/>
        <id>https://pontedarte.org/conimbriga.html</id>

        <updated>2019-09-16T18:44:23+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://pontedarte.org/media/posts/30/Conimbriga_calling_article.jpg" alt="" />
                    Conímbriga is one of the largest Roman settlements excavated in Portugal, and was classified as a National&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://pontedarte.org/media/posts/30/Conimbriga_calling_article.jpg" alt="" />
                <p><strong>Conímbriga</strong> is one of the largest <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roman_Empire" title="Roman Empire">Roman</a> settlements excavated in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Portugal" title="Portugal">Portugal</a>, and was classified as a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monuments_of_Portugal" class="mw-redirect" title="Monuments of Portugal">National Monument</a> in 1910. Located in the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Freguesia_(Portugal)" class="mw-redirect" title="Freguesia (Portugal)">civil parish</a> of Condeixa-a-Velha e Condeixa-a-Nova, in the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Concelho" title="Concelho">municipality</a> of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Condeixa-a-Nova" title="Condeixa-a-Nova">Condeixa-a-Nova</a>, it is situated 2 kilometres (1.2 mi) from the municipal seat and 16 kilometres (9.9 mi) from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coimbra" title="Coimbra">Coimbra</a> (the Roman town of <i><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aeminium" title="Aeminium">Aeminium</a></i>).</p>
<p>Conímbriga is a walled urban settlement, encircled by a curtain of stone structures approximately 1,500 metres (4,900 ft) long. Entrance to the settlement is made from vaulted structures consisting of two doors (one on hinges), and at one time was defended by two towers. The walls are paralleled by two passages, channelled to excavations, in order to remove water infiltration from the walls. The urban settlement consists of various structures such as a forum, basilica and commercial shops, thermal spas, aqueducts, insulae, homes of various heights (including interior patios) and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domus" title="Domus">domus</a> (such as the <i>Casa dos Repuxos</i> and <i>Casa de Cantaber</i>), in addition to paleo-Christian basilica.</p>
<p>A visitors' centre (which includes restaurant/café and gift-shop) was constructed to display objects found by archaeologists during their excavations, including coins, surgical tools, utensils and ceramics.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Bussaco Palace</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ponte d&#x27;Arte</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://pontedarte.org/bussaco-palace.html"/>
        <id>https://pontedarte.org/bussaco-palace.html</id>

        <updated>2019-09-16T18:48:52+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://pontedarte.org/media/posts/29/1280px-Palacio_Hotel_de_Bussaco_XL.jpg" alt="Bussaco Palace / Palácio Hotel do Buçaco" />
                    History The Bussaco Palace was built between 1888 and 1907.The palace, commissioned by&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://pontedarte.org/media/posts/29/1280px-Palacio_Hotel_de_Bussaco_XL.jpg" alt="Bussaco Palace / Palácio Hotel do Buçaco" />
                <div id="block-dexp-page-elements-dexp-page-elements-page-title" class="block block-dexp-page-elements">
<div class="content">
<div class="page_title_no_sub">
<h2 id="mcetoc_1dktfhua00" class="page_title">History</h2>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div id="block-views-hotel-block" class="block block-views">
<div class="inner"> </div>
<div class="inner">The Bussaco Palace was built between 1888 and 1907.</div>
<div class="content">
<div class="view view-hotel view-id-hotel view-display-id-block Hotel view-dom-id-e8dd7ade732ed5a92e96c1872f6bb565">
<div class="view-content">
<div class="views-row views-row-1 views-row-odd views-row-first views-row-last">
<div>
<div class="text">
<p>The palace, commissioned by King Charles I of Portugal as a royal retreat, embodies the contemporaneous architectural fashion known as castle romanticism ( German: Burgenromantik) and all the national enthusiasm for the Age of the Discoveries.</p>
<p>By late 19th century, many castles were picturesquely constructed and abandoned castles were transformed into historic palaces - Neuschwanstein Castle, Lichtenstein Castle, Hohenzollern Castle, Stolzenfels Castle, Wartburg Castle and the Château de Pierrefonds are major examples of this trend. Charles, Ferdinand of Saxe-Coburg Gotha’s grandson, was naturally influenced by this ideal.</p>
<p>Initial ideas for the palace drew stylistically on a Falkenstein Castle, Ludwig II of Bavaria’s project that never left planning stages, to be built on the western slope of the hill, by the Coimbra Gates, but were quickly replaced by increasingly extensive drafts culminating in a Neo-Manueline style palace, modeled on the Belém Tower of Lisbon, the major symbol of the Portuguese Discoveries. Also the projected location was transferred to the site of the convent, so that part of it could be transformed into the new palace, matching the romantic ideal of a knight’s castle, hidden from view by dense, skyscraping trees. The young King’s romantic vision of a picturesque new Belém Tower amidst a tranquil green botanic ocean had to be fulfilled …</p>
<p>The building design was drafted by the Italian architect and National Opera House stage designer Luigi Manini, brought to Portugal by Queen Maria Pia of Savoy, Charles’s mother, and daughter of Victor Emmanuel II of Italy. He drafted a Romantic palace in Neo-Manueline gothic style, evoking the 16th-century architectural style that characterized the peak of the Portuguese Age of Discovery.</p>
<p>Manini was succeeded by architects Nicola Bigaglia, José Alexandre Soares and Manuel Joaquim Norte Júnior, the latter responsible for the annex “Casa dos Brasões” (House of the Coat-of-Arms), and also for the extraordinary Curia Palace and for the renowned “Café a Brasileira”, in Lisbon.</p>
<p>The inner rooms are richly decorated with Neo-Manueline portals and stucco work imitating Manueline rib vaulting, being also an important showcase of Portuguese painting and sculpture of the early 20th century. The inner walls are also decorated with tile (azulejos) panels by Jorge Colaço. These panels depict scenes taken from Portuguese literature as well as historical events like the Battle of Bussaco.</p>
<p>In 1885 - exactly one year after Ludwig II moved to the still unfinished Neuschwanstein Castle - the dining hall , the kitchen, the library and some cells of the convent were demolished and the foundation stone was laid.</p>
<p>The palace was erected as a conventional brick construction and later encased with other types of rock, mainly limestone from a nearby quarry, sandstone from nearby Ançã, and marble from Vila Viçosa, in the Alentejo. The forest also provided essential conifers, oak, and chestnut premium quality woods.</p>
<p>For about 25 years the construction site was the principal employer of the region and of all major Portuguese artists of the period.</p>
<p>The palace consists of several individual structures, and the main building – a flurry of excesses and a hotchpotch of styles - is furnished with a rectangular tower overlooking the Atlantic coastline, ornamental turrets, gables and gargoyles, balconies, pinnacles, arches and sculptures.</p>
<p>Following Romanesque style, some windows openings are fashioned as bi- and triforia.</p>
<p>Unlike “real” castles, Bussaco Palace was planned from the inception as an intentionally asymmetric building, and erected in consecutive stages. Typical attributes of a castle were included, but real fortifications – the most important feature of a medieval aristocratic estate – were dispensed with.</p>
<p>Today the palace is a fully functioning luxury hotel, and can be visited as part of a tour of the Bussaco complex.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Celia de Villiers</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ponte d&#x27;Arte</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://pontedarte.org/celia-de-villiers.html"/>
        <id>https://pontedarte.org/celia-de-villiers.html</id>

        <updated>2019-09-17T23:22:14+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://pontedarte.org/media/posts/28/celia.jpg" alt="" />
                    BiographyCelia de Villiers has three tertiary qualifications, including a MA in Visual&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://pontedarte.org/media/posts/28/celia.jpg" alt="" />
                <h3 id="mcetoc_1dkb61pgh0">Biography</h3>
<p>Celia de Villiers has three tertiary qualifications, including a MA in Visual Arts (cum laude). A fellow of the the Sacatar foundation of California, she has also been credited by the World Craft Council, and endorsed by UNESCO. She has exhibited, curated and adjudicated extensively in South Africa and abroad, as well as presented and published academic articles in South Africa, the United States, Brazil, Romania, Belgium and France.</p>
<p>Her two and three-dimensional artworks in various media are held in corporate, museum and private collections such as the Raiffeisen Bank, Germany, Landesbank, Germany, Le Tousserok Sun International Hotel, Mauritius, UNISA, EnviroServ and the Development Bank, South Africa, Michigan State University, and the Museum of Art and Design, New York.</p>
<p>The artist has facilitated and consulted for community outreach and social art initiatives for eighteen years, and won government awards for job creation in the arts and crafts sector in South Africa. She has served on the board of the UNISA gallery, the EnviroServ WasteArt Foundation, the SA government department of Arts and Culture, and the SA Bureau of Standards for Craft.</p>
<p>De Villiers has lectured in Drawing, Painting, Sculpture, Conceptualisation and Art theory from first to postgraduate level at the University of South Africa, The Design School of South Africa and the University of Pretoria between 2001 to 2018, as well as presenting workshops internationally.</p>
<p>She relocated from South Africa to Europe in 2015, where she spends her time between Belgium and Portugal. Most recently she has been a guest lecturer at the Royal Academy of Art in Antwerp (2015 -2018), engaged in a European Union funded project between universities in Dublin, Ireland, Turku, Finland and Zagreb, Croatia (2016 - 2018).</p>
<p>She is a co-director of Ponte d’ Arte, an Artistic Hub and Residency near Coimbra, Portugal, whilst remaining a passionate crafter and artist.</p>
<p>See her work at <a href="http://www.celiadevilliers.com">http://www.celiadevilliers.com</a>.</p>
<p>Celia joins Kris as artist mentor on his popular <a href="https://pontedarte.org/master-classes.html">In Situ3 Master Classes</a><strong>.</strong></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Kris van ‘t Hof</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ponte d&#x27;Arte</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://pontedarte.org/kris-van-t-hof.html"/>
        <id>https://pontedarte.org/kris-van-t-hof.html</id>

        <updated>2019-09-17T23:20:30+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://pontedarte.org/media/posts/27/kris-and-sheep.jpg" alt="" />
                    BiographyKris van ‘t Hof designs, co-produces and teaches situation-specific art projects and&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://pontedarte.org/media/posts/27/kris-and-sheep.jpg" alt="" />
                <h3 id="mcetoc_1dkr6v5vd0">Biography</h3>
<p>Kris van ‘t Hof designs, co-produces and teaches situation-specific art projects and practices. He specialised in Monumental and Environmental Arts at the Royal Academy of Fine Arts (KASKA), Antwerp, BE, and at Masters of Fine Art level at the National Higher Institute of Fine Arts (HISK). He is teaching in the <em>In Situ</em> department and also lectures in figure drawing and conceptual art up to post-graduate level at KASKA. He was awarded a fellowship in arts-and-cultural heritage by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation in 2014.</p>
<p>Van ‘t Hof organises international workshops and study trips promoting transnational artworks and the collaboration of artists. He has been a guest professor at Universities in Krakow, La Laguna, Turku, Roma, Oslo, Athina, Delphi, Rethymnon, Syros &amp; Hydra, Sofia, Varna, Praha, Porto, Lisbon, Leiria, Dublin, Sevilla and Zagreb in Europe, Sarasota (US), Pretoria, Midrand and Johannesburg (South Africa).</p>
<p>He has adjudicated several art competitions in Europe and has received numerous awards for his own artworks, such as from OPEL, Belgium. Van t’ Hof has completed eighteen public art projects (two-and three-dimensional works) and designed stage sets, amongst them for the National Opera in Brussels and the Royal Ballet in Flanders. His paintings are in private and corporate collections worldwide.</p>
<p>Most recently (2015 – 2018) he has been engaged in IPIP (<em>In Public in Particular</em>) with art academies in Turku, Dublin, Zagreb and Antwerp, funded by Creative Europe. Its manifestations included social interactive projects, performance art happenings and collaborative community parades in Antwerp, BE, art-directed and co-ordinated by Van t' Hof.</p>
<p>A key component of this research concerns the engagement and development of audiences; specifically focused on working in local situations and small neighbourhoods. Practice-led research reports are available for download (<a href="http://ipip-project.eu">http://ipip-project.eu</a>) and in print (<em>In public in particular - art and exchange in four European cities, </em>November 2018).</p>
<p>With the South African artist Celia de Villiers, Kris Van ‘t Hof co-directs the residency and teaching programme at Ponte d’ Arte (Arts Bridge), in Ponte da Mucela, near Coimbra in central Portugal.</p>
<p> See his work at http://<a href="http://www.krisvanthof.com">www.krisvanthof.com</a> </p>
<p>Kris is the artist mentor on the popular <a href="https://pontedarte.org/workshops/">In Situ3 Master Classes</a><strong>.</strong></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>The Adega</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ponte d&#x27;Arte</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://pontedarte.org/the-adega-library-and-meetings.html"/>
        <id>https://pontedarte.org/the-adega-library-and-meetings.html</id>

        <updated>2019-09-17T21:32:04+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://pontedarte.org/media/posts/26/IMG_20190915_125215.jpg" alt="The Adega at Ponte d&#x27;Arte Portugal" />
                    The Adega (former wine press) houses a meeting space, library for small&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://pontedarte.org/media/posts/26/IMG_20190915_125215.jpg" alt="The Adega at Ponte d&#x27;Arte Portugal" />
                <p>The Adega (former wine press) houses a meeting space, library for small groups (10 people max).  It includes a kitchen, dining area and patio.</p>
<div class="gallery"   >
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://pontedarte.org/media/posts/26/gallery/IMG_20190308_145621-HDR2-.jpg" ><img src="https://pontedarte.org/media/posts/26/gallery/IMG_20190308_145621-HDR2--thumbnail.jpg" alt="" width="768" height="1024"></a></figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://pontedarte.org/media/posts/26/gallery/IMG_20190915_125239.jpg" ><img src="https://pontedarte.org/media/posts/26/gallery/IMG_20190915_125239-thumbnail.jpg" alt="" width="768" height="576"></a></figure>
</div>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>The Garden</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ponte d&#x27;Arte</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://pontedarte.org/the-garden.html"/>
        <id>https://pontedarte.org/the-garden.html</id>

        <updated>2019-09-16T20:03:13+02:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://pontedarte.org/media/posts/25/P1010071-2.jpg" alt="" />
                <div class="gallery"   >
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://pontedarte.org/media/posts/25/gallery/2019-insta-ponte-5.jpg" ><img src="https://pontedarte.org/media/posts/25/gallery/2019-insta-ponte-5-thumbnail.jpg" alt="" width="768" height="960"></a></figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://pontedarte.org/media/posts/25/gallery/2019-insta-ponte-8.jpg" ><img src="https://pontedarte.org/media/posts/25/gallery/2019-insta-ponte-8-thumbnail.jpg" alt="" width="768" height="960"></a></figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://pontedarte.org/media/posts/25/gallery/2019-Instagram-pontedarte-Aug142.jpg" ><img src="https://pontedarte.org/media/posts/25/gallery/2019-Instagram-pontedarte-Aug142-thumbnail.jpg" alt="" width="768" height="960"></a></figure>
</div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
