<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Ponte d&#x27;Arte, Portugal</title>
    <link href="https://pontedarte.org/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://pontedarte.org" />
    <updated>2019-09-10T00:26:49+02:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Ponte d&#x27;Arte</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://pontedarte.org</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Conimbriga</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ponte d&#x27;Arte</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://pontedarte.org/conimbriga.html"/>
        <id>https://pontedarte.org/conimbriga.html</id>

        <updated>2019-09-09T16:07:44+02:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Bussaco Palace</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ponte d&#x27;Arte</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://pontedarte.org/bussaco-palace.html"/>
        <id>https://pontedarte.org/bussaco-palace.html</id>

        <updated>2019-09-09T23:49:56+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://pontedarte.org/media/posts/29/1280px-Palacio_Hotel_de_Bussaco_XL.jpg" alt="Bussaco Palace / Palácio Hotel do Buçaco" />
                    The Neo-Manueline was a revival architecture and decorative arts style developed in Portugal&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://pontedarte.org/media/posts/29/1280px-Palacio_Hotel_de_Bussaco_XL.jpg" alt="Bussaco Palace / Palácio Hotel do Buçaco" />
                The Neo-Manueline was a revival architecture and decorative arts style developed in Portugal between the middle of the 19th century and the beginning of the 20th century. The style adopted the characteristics of the Manueline (or Portuguese Final Gothic) of the 16th century.
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Celia de Villiers</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ponte d&#x27;Arte</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://pontedarte.org/celia-de-villiers.html"/>
        <id>https://pontedarte.org/celia-de-villiers.html</id>

        <updated>2019-09-09T16:17:25+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://pontedarte.org/media/posts/28/celia-de-villiers_web2.jpg" alt="" />
                    BiographyCelia de Villiers holds a MA in Visual Arts Cum laude (UNISA),&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://pontedarte.org/media/posts/28/celia-de-villiers_web2.jpg" alt="" />
                <h3 id="mcetoc_1dkb61pgh0">Biography</h3>
<p>Celia de Villiers holds a MA in Visual Arts Cum laude (UNISA), BA Fine Art (UNISA) with distinction and a Higher Education Diploma (Wits). She has exhibited extensively, locally and abroad and curates and adjudicates exhibitions, including The Thami Mnyele Awards in Ekurhuleni (2009, 2011), The Department of Arts and Culture National Craft Awards (2009), PPC Young Sculptors Awards (2010), National judge (2008) for the 23rd ABSA L’ Atelier Awards and regional judge for the 26th, 27th L’ Atelier Awards (2011, 2012).</p>
<p>De Villiers has been a Standard Bank Resident Artist at the National Arts festival. Her sculptures in various media are in permanent collections such as the Raiffeisen Bank, Germany, Le Tousserok Sun International Hotel, Mauritius, Development Bank of South Africa, UNISA, Michigan State University, and the Museum of Art and Design, New York. She was awarded an art fellowship by the Sacatar foundation of California in 2004.</p>
<p>The artist travels to venues outside Gauteng to facilitate and consult for the Arts Inter Action community outreach initiative and was a board member of the Enviroserv WasteArt Foundation for 8 years. De Villiers was nominated as a finalist for the Woman of Substance (Mosadi wa Kono-kono) by the Gauteng provincial government in 2006 and was a University of South Africa nominee for the Shoprite/Checkers Woman of the Year and the winner of Ekurhuleni Mayoral Achievers Award for Job Creation in the Arts and Crafts sector during 2006. She received a marketing excellence award from UNISA in 2009 and served on the Advisory Board for craft of the South African Department of Arts and Culture from 2008-2010.</p>
<p>De Villiers has lectured in Drawing, Painting Sculpture, and Conceptual art from first to post-graduate level at the University of South Africa from 2001-2011. She is currently lecturing part-time at the Design school of South Africa, UNISA and Pretoria University. Her artworks and articles have appeared in numerous publications. She has presented research papers at the World Environmental Education Conference (2007), the European Fibre Art Convention in Val d’ Argent, France (2004, 2008, 2009), the University of Pretoria (2009, 2011), the Universities of Bahia (2004) and University of Cachoeira (2010) in Salvador, Brazil, Stendhal University-Grenoble, France (2008), the University of Johannesburg in 2011 and was a keynote speaker the University of Alba Iulia in Romania (2010).</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Kris van ‘t Hof</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ponte d&#x27;Arte</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://pontedarte.org/kris-van-t-hof.html"/>
        <id>https://pontedarte.org/kris-van-t-hof.html</id>

        <updated>2019-09-09T15:58:53+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                     Kris van ‘t Hof designs, co-produces and teaches situation-specific art projects&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p> </p>
<h3 id="mcetoc_1dkb502sf1">Biography</h3>
<p>Kris van ‘t Hof designs, co-produces and teaches situation-specific art projects and practices. He specialised in Monumental and Environmental Arts at the Royal Academy of Fine Arts (KASKA), Antwerp, BE, and at Masters of Fine Art level at the National Higher Institute of Fine Arts (HISK). He is teaching in the <em>In Situ</em> department and also lectures in figure drawing and conceptual art up to post-graduate level at KASKA. He was awarded a fellowship in arts-and-cultural heritage by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation in 2014.</p>
<p>Van ‘t Hof organises international workshops and study trips promoting transnational artworks and the collaboration of artists. He has been a guest professor at Universities in Krakow, La Laguna, Turku, Roma, Oslo, Athina, Delphi, Rethymnon, Syros &amp; Hydra, Sofia, Varna, Praha, Porto, Lisbon, Leiria, Dublin, Sevilla and Zagreb in Europe, Sarasota (US), Pretoria, Midrand and Johannesburg (South Africa).</p>
<p>He has adjudicated several art competitions in Europe and has received numerous awards for his own artworks, such as from OPEL, Belgium. Van t’ Hof has completed eighteen public art projects (two-and three-dimensional works) and designed stage sets, amongst them for the National Opera in Brussels and the Royal Ballet in Flanders. His paintings are in private and corporate collections worldwide.</p>
<p>Most recently (2015 – 2018) he has been engaged in IPIP (<em>In Public in Particular</em>) with art academies in Turku, Dublin, Zagreb and Antwerp, funded by Creative Europe. Its manifestations included social interactive projects, performance art happenings and collaborative community parades in Antwerp, BE, art-directed and co-ordinated by Van T’Hof.</p>
<p>A key component of this research concerns the engagement and development of audiences; specifically focused on working in local situations and small neighbourhoods. Practice-led research reports are available for download (<a href="http://ipip-project.eu">http://ipip-project.eu</a>) and in print (<em>In public in particular - art and exchange in four European cities, </em>November 2018).</p>
<p>With the South African artist Celia de Villiers, Kris Van ‘t Hof co-directs the residency and teaching programme at Ponte d’ Arte (Arts Bridge), in Ponte da Mucela, near Coimbra in central Portugal.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Contact:</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p><a href="mailto:kris.vanthof@ap.be">kris.vanthof@ap.be</a></p>
<p>ponte.d.arte.portugal@gmail.com</p>
<p>Studio: 0032 473 91 62 27</p>
<p>http://<a href="http://www.krisvanthof.com">www.krisvanthof.com</a> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>The Adega (library &amp; meetings)</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ponte d&#x27;Arte</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://pontedarte.org/the-adega-library-and-meetings.html"/>
        <id>https://pontedarte.org/the-adega-library-and-meetings.html</id>

        <updated>2019-09-09T15:47:52+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Kitchen, dining room, library (adega) meeting space for small groups (10 people&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Kitchen, dining room, library (adega) meeting space for small groups (10 people max).</span></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>The Garden</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ponte d&#x27;Arte</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://pontedarte.org/the-garden.html"/>
        <id>https://pontedarte.org/the-garden.html</id>

        <updated>2019-09-10T00:20:11+02:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Riverside</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ponte d&#x27;Arte</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://pontedarte.org/riverside.html"/>
        <id>https://pontedarte.org/riverside.html</id>

        <updated>2019-09-10T00:24:44+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://pontedarte.org/media/posts/24/Ponte-De-Mucela-27.jpg" alt="" />
                    Camping site and river beach, future site for outdoor sculpture installations
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://pontedarte.org/media/posts/24/Ponte-De-Mucela-27.jpg" alt="" />
                <span style="font-weight: 400;">Camping site and river beach, future site for outdoor sculpture installations</span>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>The Rio Alva</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ponte d&#x27;Arte</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://pontedarte.org/the-rio-alva.html"/>
        <id>https://pontedarte.org/the-rio-alva.html</id>

        <updated>2019-09-10T00:26:00+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://pontedarte.org/media/posts/23/Ponte-De-Mucela-79.jpg" alt="" />
                    Swimming, caoneing, etc
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://pontedarte.org/media/posts/23/Ponte-De-Mucela-79.jpg" alt="" />
                <span style="font-weight: 400;">Swimming, caoneing, etc</span>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Chinese Summer Drawing Class - 2016</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ponte d&#x27;Arte</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://pontedarte.org/chinese-summer-drawing-class-2016.html"/>
        <id>https://pontedarte.org/chinese-summer-drawing-class-2016.html</id>

        <updated>2019-09-09T15:42:49+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    AThinkTank Station, artistic hub for artists Ponte da Mucela,Portugal Programme: Diverse angles&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><strong>AThinkTank Station, artistic hub for artists Ponte da Mucela,Portugal</strong></p>
<p><strong>Programme:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Diverse angles with a different objective in mind each day (contrast, rhythm, linear qualities,</strong></p>
<p><strong>Composition, perspectives…).</strong></p>
<br>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Broken by time – engaging with ‘the lie of the land’ - 2016</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ponte d&#x27;Arte</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://pontedarte.org/broken-by-time-engaging-with-the-lie-of-the-land-2016.html"/>
        <id>https://pontedarte.org/broken-by-time-engaging-with-the-lie-of-the-land-2016.html</id>

        <updated>2019-09-09T15:33:50+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    In Situ3 – Workshop September 2016 The Collins English Dictionary explains "the&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><strong>In Situ</strong><strong>3</strong> <span style="font-weight: 400;">– </span><strong>Workshop   September 2016</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Collins English Dictionary explains "<em>t</em></span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">he lie of the land"</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in two ways:</span></p>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">         The</span><a href="http://www.collinsdictionary.com/dictionary/english/topography"> <strong>topography</strong></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> of the land,</span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">         The way in which a</span><a href="http://www.collinsdictionary.com/dictionary/english/situation"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">situation</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is developing and </span><strong>people are</strong><a href="http://www.collinsdictionary.com/dictionary/english/behave"> <strong>behaving</strong></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">These are essentially the 2 main concepts we will be considering during this In Situ</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">3</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> workshop.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<p><strong>Nature and land</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in this context includes the physical world and everything in it - such as plants, animals, mountains, fossils, rocks, oceans and even stars in the universe. </span></p>
<p>This In Situ workshop is essentially orientated towards contemplation about the manner in which elements in the environment are gradually remodelled or transformed over time - either by natural forces or by processes due to human intervention. </p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
