<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Ponte d&#x27;Arte, Portugal</title>
    <link href="https://pontedarte.org/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://pontedarte.org" />
    <updated>2020-05-05T07:28:25+02:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Ponte d&#x27;Arte</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://pontedarte.org</id>

    <entry>
        <title>New site specific artworks by Lana Steiler, Artist in Residence </title>
        <author>
            <name>Ponte d&#x27;Arte</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://pontedarte.org/lana-steiler-french-artist-in-situ-site-specific.html"/>
        <id>https://pontedarte.org/lana-steiler-french-artist-in-situ-site-specific.html</id>

        <updated>2020-05-05T07:28:09+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://pontedarte.org/media/posts/37/Lana-Steiler-9.jpg" alt="Track/Tack/Stack, an in situ artwork by Lana Steiler" />
                    A peek into Lana Steiler's mobile working and living space.Lana Steiler is an&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://pontedarte.org/media/posts/37/Lana-Steiler-9.jpg" alt="Track/Tack/Stack, an in situ artwork by Lana Steiler" />
                <figure class="post__image undefined" ><img src="https://pontedarte.org/media/posts/37/van1.jpg" alt="" width="1600" height="1067">
<figcaption >A peek into Lana Steiler's mobile working and living space.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Lana Steiler is an artist who inherits from the movements of Land Art and art in situ. The roots of her work lie in the concepts of ​​motions and stops, travels and breaks, itineraries and camps. After graduating from the École Supérieure d'Art Annecy Alpes, in 2019, she went on a self-residency for five months, crisscrossing Spain and Portugal. Her only workshop spaces were the place she set up camp in and her old Mercedes van.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Throughout her journeys, she questions the use of natural and uninhabited spaces. It is through her wanderings and encounters that she takes part in the history of different environments and materials they comprise of. She gives substance to that purpose by creating mainly sculptures and in situ installations. She deeply involves her whole body and mind in each place she explores, with the notion of toil as her leitmotif. Her art is inspired by the gestures of peasants or craftsmen, whose work remains consistent even in bad weather. Concerned about her ecological impact, her work is also animated by the idea of not adding to the environment and its elements, but rather to "do with.” Like the forms she creates, Lana does not impose her presence but tries to blend herself into her workspace by shedding light on what is already there.</span></p>
<figure class="post__image post__image--center"><img src="https://pontedarte.org/media/posts/37/Lana-Steiler-portrait.jpg" alt="Lana Steiler at Ponte d'Arte in her mobile studio" width="284" height="400">
<figcaption >Lana Steiler and mobile studio, Ponte d'Arte, February 2020.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ponte d'Arte in Portugal was the last stop of her roaming in 2020. She stayed for five weeks  and produced three sculptures here. The first two, <em>Calor Pintura</em> and <em>[prɪˈkɛəriəs]</em>, were made in a ruin, located in a garden. Its tiled roof had completely collapsed after the Iberian Fire disaster of 2017. The third sculpture, <em>Track/Tack/Stack</em>, was made in Moura Morta, on a cliff face, along the Alva River.</span></p>
<blockquote>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br>"At the entrance of this ruin, you will glimpse a space punctuated by three assemblies of tiles on the ground, separated by empty areas.  </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the center is a bed of collapsed tiles left unaltered. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">On the left, the broken form of Calor Pintura, (Portuguese for “Heat Painting”) embodies disaster. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">On the right, in a cleaned-up corner,  [prɪˈkɛəriəs] (phonetic spelling of “precarious”), plays with the possibility of reconstruction. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Between the two, a clear path is drawn. The whole space thus takes into account the concept of time.”<br><br>- Lana Steiler</span></p>
</blockquote>
<br>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1e7gqlepe4"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Calor Pintura</span></h2>
<figure class="post__image undefined" ><img src="https://pontedarte.org/media/posts/37/CalorPinturaDetail.jpg" alt="Calor Pintura, an in situ sculpture by Lana Steiler, 5mx2mx3m" width="800" height="534">
<figcaption >Calor Pintura, an in situ sculpture by Lana Steiler at Ponte d'Arte, 5mx2mx3m</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>“Calor Pintura is a sculpture inspired by the fire in 2017. This story moved me a lot and the remaining traces of this tragic event visually seduced me. One of the interior walls of the ruin retains shades of black, gray, blue, and white. It is by observing this fire-made painting that I noticed that the tiles, too, had been tinted by the different degrees of burning they suffered. I then arranged them on the ground, keeping positioning unstructured to respect the general shape in which I had found them. By sorting them according to their colors and matching the colors of the wall against which I placed them, I could understand the different intensities of heat during the fire. Thus, little by little, a gradient formed, passing from dark gray to yellow and red .</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As a gradation of burnt pigments, the sculpture that became a painting took on meaning in this place as its history became obvious to me by observation.”</span></p>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1e7gql62b3"><span style="font-weight: 400;">[prɪˈkɛəriəs]</span></h2>
<p> </p>
<figure class="post__image undefined"><img src="https://pontedarte.org/media/posts/37/prIkerisWide.jpg" alt="[prɪˈkɛəriəs], an in situ sculpture by Lana Steiler at Ponte d'Arte, 1m40x3m20x2m70" width="800" height="590">
<figcaption >[prɪˈkɛəriəs], an in situ sculpture by Lana Steiler at Ponte d'Arte, 1m40x3m20x2m70</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="post__image post__image"><img src="https://pontedarte.org/media/posts/37/prIkerisDetail.jpg" alt="[prɪˈkɛəriəs], an in situ sculpture by Lana Steiler at Ponte d'Arte, 1m40x3m20x2m70" width="800" height="600">
<figcaption >[prɪˈkɛəriəs], an in situ sculpture by Lana Steiler at Ponte d'Arte, 1m40x3m20x2m70, (detail).</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="post__image post__image"><img src="https://pontedarte.org/media/posts/37/prIkerisDetail-2.jpg" alt="[prɪˈkɛəriəs], an in situ sculpture by Lana Steiler at Ponte d'Arte, 1m40x3m20x2m70" width="600" height="800">
<figcaption >[prɪˈkɛəriəs], an in situ sculpture by Lana Steiler at Ponte d'Arte, 1m40x3m20x2m70, (detail).</figcaption>
</figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">"[prɪˈkɛəriəs] is a sculpture installed in the same space as Calor Pintura. Impatient as an archaeologist wanting to decipher the history of a place before and during a past disaster, I first cleared an area on the ground. This step created a workspace, an in situ workshop. I manipulated the tiles towards the natural stacking their shape induced by its design, with the hope of reconstructing what had been demolished and, by doing so,  giving them back their original function. So, little by little and despite the bad weather, I assembled them as high as I could, playing with the breaking points. This gave rise to balanced forms, resistant to rain and wind. The final assembly of these tiles became a carapace-like shelter, restoringtheir function before. The sculpture overlooks and faces the rest of the disaster."</span></p>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1e7gqktgk2" class="post__image">Track/Tack/Stack</h2>
<figure class="post__image undefined"><img src="https://pontedarte.org/media/posts/37/TrackTackStackWide1.jpg" alt="The site of Track/Tack/Stack, an in situ artwork by Lana Steiler at Moura Morta on the Alva River, 6mx3mx4,20m" width="800" height="600">
<figcaption >The site of Track/Tack/Stack, in situ artwork by Lana Steiler, Moura Morta, Alva River near Ponte d'Arte, 6mx3mx4,20m</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="post__image undefined"><img src="https://pontedarte.org/media/posts/37/TrackTackStackWide2.jpg" alt="Track/Tack/Stack, an in situ artwork by Lana Steiler, 6mx3mx4,20m" width="800" height="519">
<figcaption >Track/Tack/Stack, an in situ artwork by Lana Steiler, 6mx3mx4,20m</figcaption>
</figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">"As I walked along the shale cliffs, I spotted a chunk of the mountain slowly collapsing. My desire then was to repair or rebuild it.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">At the time, lockdown due to COVID-19 had just been decreed. I was thinking a lot about care. Each day, for more than a week, I went to that place to take care of it. I first cleared all the debris and cleaned up the cliff to begin construction on a solid rock base. Afterward, I filled all the breaches and interstices by wedging shale plates face to face to reproduce their natural state. My intent was to give back to the solid cliff all the stones it had lost. By reconstructing it upwards, the lines and amalgams of rock finally create the illusion of a downward flow. It was then that the flow of the Alva River below offered a sound dimension to the sculpture. Later, I related this new form to the situation of the COVID-19 pandemic, making conscious the ideas of ​​collapse, attempted reconstruction, and life which, despite interruption, continues to flow."</span></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title> Announcing our 2019 Writer In Residence: Alfredo J. Ferreiro Salgueiro</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ponte d&#x27;Arte</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://pontedarte.org/announcing-our-2019-writer-in-residence-alfredo-j-ferreiro-salgueiro.html"/>
        <id>https://pontedarte.org/announcing-our-2019-writer-in-residence-alfredo-j-ferreiro-salgueiro.html</id>

        <updated>2020-01-23T11:15:30+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://pontedarte.org/media/posts/36/e68d9963e82646bca7e910c39420c2ae.jpeg" alt="Alfredo J Ferreiro Salgueiro" />
                     In the beginning / there was a tear. / A line&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://pontedarte.org/media/posts/36/e68d9963e82646bca7e910c39420c2ae.jpeg" alt="Alfredo J Ferreiro Salgueiro" />
                <blockquote>
<p><br>In the beginning / there was a tear. / A line of tears / hardened / and hit the bones./ The bones burned / and of its flame / surged the flesh./ The flesh was made light / and from his leavening / hair was born / Hair like wind / did not want to be trapped / and by the airy feeling / hovered the soul./ The soul dwelled alone / on top of the mountain, / but when another stumbled / smiled / and from her flowed / a tear <br><br>- Alfredo Ferreiro Salgueiro, from the book Theory of Ruins </p>
</blockquote>
<p>We are pleased to announce that our first writer in residence the multilingual Galician poet is Alfredo J. Ferreiro Salgueiro.  He is the author of four books of poetry, Theory of Ruins (Poetics Edições, Braga, 2019), Fateful Verses (Edicións Positivas, Santiago de Compostela, 2011), Central Metal (Espiral Maior, Corunha, 2009) and A Cidade Engrinaldada (Cadernos de Azertyuiop, nº 7, Corunha, 1997). He co-founded and co-directs <a href="palavracomum.com">Palavra Comum</a> (Common Word), the digital arts and letters magazine. His personal page, “<a href="alfredoferreiro.com">The Minesweeper</a>” won the award for the best AELG literary blog (2011). He is a member of the Galician Language Writers Association and the Galician Language Association, and was a member of the Galician Surrealist Group. He coordinates several reading clubs, as well as the Manuel Murguia de Arteijo Brief Narration Event. Learn more about <a href="http://alfredoferreiro.com/sobre-who-write/obra/">Alfredo here</a>. </p>
<p>This unique residency is open to a Portuguese language poet or writer inspired by the theme of wildfires. Alfredo receives receives twelve days of accommodation in our quiet riverside apartment away from the city, including meals and transport from Coimbra. Alfredo will conclude his stay presenting a text at "<a href="https://pontedarte.org/resiliencia-exhibition-art-music-poetry-2019.html">Resiliência</a>", our multi-lingual community art celebration on 13 October 2019, presenting alongside international contemporary artists and students who participated in a site-specific art workshop on the theme.</p>
<p>Thank you to all those who applied, and good luck for next year's residency!   </p>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1dlsev76a0">Anunciando nosso escritor em residência 2019: Alfredo J. Ferreiro Salgueiro</h2>
<blockquote>
<p><br>No princípio/ houve uma lágrima./ Uma fila de lágrimas/ endureceu-se / e deu nos ossos./ Os ossos arderam/ e da sua chama/ surgiu a carne./ A carne fez-se leve/ e da sua levedação/ nasceram os cabelos/ Os cabelos como vento/ não queriam ficar presos/ e pelo aéreo sentimento/ pairou a alma./ A alma morava só/ no cume da montanha,/ mas quando outra topou/ sorriu/ e dela manou/ uma lágrima <br><br>- Alfredo Ferreiro Salgueiro, do livro Teoria das Ruínas</p>
</blockquote>
<p dir="ltr">Temos o prazer de anunciar que o nosso primeiro escritor em residência o poeta galego multilíngue é Alfredo J. Ferreiro Salgueiro.  É autor de quatro livros de poesia, Teoria das Ruínas (Poética Edições, Braga, 2019), Versos Fatídicos (Edicións Positivas, Santiago de Compostela, 2011), Metal Central (Espiral Maior, Corunha, 2009) e A Cidade Engrinaldada (Cadernos de Azertyuiop, nº 7, Corunha, 1997). Co-fundou e co-dirige a revista digital de artes e letras <a href="palavracomum.com">Palavra Comum</a>. Sua página pessoal é “<a href="alfredoferreiro.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">O levantador de minas</a>”, com que venceu o prémio do melhor blogue literário da AELG em 2011. É membro da Associação de Escritores em Língua Galega e da Associação Galega da Língua. Foi membro do Grupo Surrealista Galego. Coordena vários clubes de leitura, assim como o Certame de Narrações Breves Manuel Murguia de Arteijo. Saiba mais sobre <a href="http://alfredoferreiro.com/sobre-quem-escreve/obra/">Alfredo aqui</a>.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Esta residência única é aberta a um poeta ou escritor de língua portuguesa inspirado no tema dos incêndios. Alfredo recebe recebe doze dias de acomodação em nosso tranquilo apartamento à beira-rio, longe da cidade, incluindo refeições e transporte de Coimbra. Alfredo concluirá sua estadia apresentando um texto na "<a href="https://pontedarte.org/resiliencia-exhibition-art-music-poetry-2019.html">Resiliência</a>", nossa celebração de arte comunitária multilíngue em 13 de outubro de 2019, apresentando-se ao lado de artistas contemporâneos internacionais e estudantes que participaram de um workshop de arte específico sobre o tema.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Obrigado a todos que se inscreveram e boa sorte para a residência do próximo ano!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Lousã</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ponte d&#x27;Arte</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://pontedarte.org/lousa.html"/>
        <id>https://pontedarte.org/lousa.html</id>

        <updated>2019-09-18T22:46:13+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://pontedarte.org/media/posts/35/Lousa.jpg" alt="" />
                    The Lousã Mountain (Serra da Lousã) uniquely combines the cultural and human&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://pontedarte.org/media/posts/35/Lousa.jpg" alt="" />
                <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Lousã Mountain (Serra da Lousã) uniquely combines the cultural and human aspects of the </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Schist Villages</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> with the natural environment and leisure opportunities that its landscape offers.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It is home to red deer, wild boar and roe deer that peek through the cork oaks, chestnut trees, oaks and, of course, pines. Science suggests that the gold-striped salamander (Chioglossa lusitanica) originated here. Of the 27 schist villages in central Portugal, five are situated in Lousã and make for pleasurable day of walking.  The mountain is crossed by numerous</span><a href="http://aldeiasdoxisto.pt/category/caminhadas-e-passeios"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">hiking</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">/</span><a href="http://aldeiasdoxisto.pt/category/bicicleta"><span style="font-weight: 400;">mountain biking</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> trails and paths that lead us to</span><a href="http://aldeiasdoxisto.pt/en/poi/33"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">St. António da Neve</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, Alto do Trevim,</span><a href="http://aldeiasdoxisto.pt/en/poi/75"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Lousã Castle</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> or to the</span><a href="http://aldeiasdoxisto.pt/en/poi/76"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Shrine of Our Lady of Mercy</span></a>,<span style="font-weight: 400;"> not forgetting the</span><a href="http://aldeiasdoxisto.pt/category/praias-fluviais"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">river beaches</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Serra da Lousã, together with the</span><a href="http://aldeiasdoxisto.pt/en/node/231"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Açor Mountain</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and the Serra da Estrela, form the most imposing of Portugal’s mountain ranges: the Central Cordillera. The Lousã Mountain forms the southwest edge of this cordillera. Being formed primarily of Pre-Cambrian schist, it is therefore geologically very old. These mountain ranges also form the watershed between the river basins of the Mondego and the Tagus. The Serra da Lousã covers the municipalities of Lousã, Góis, Castanheira de Pêra, Miranda do Corvo and Figueiró dos Vinhos.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It slopes steeply down to almost flat plains that stretch northwest. It is deeply incised by watercourses, the most important of which are the Ribeira de Pena to the north, the Ribeira de São João to the northwest, and the Ribeira de Pera and Ribeira de Alge to the south. To the east looms the quartzite ridge of the</span><a href="http://aldeiasdoxisto.pt/en/poi/36"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Penedos de Góis</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. However, its highest point is Alto do Trevim at 1204 metres.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">On the paths in its woods, red deer cross our path or we hear the roar of the rut in the distance. Roe deer also occur here, but are more difficult to spot. When</span><a href="http://aldeiasdoxisto.pt/season/outono"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">autumn</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> brings its colours to the deciduous broadleaf trees, the woodland flowers turn into honey.</span></p>
<p>Plan your walking route and stop overs at <a href="https://aldeiasdoxisto.pt/en/poi/35?type=All&amp;field_season_tid=All&amp;field_tourism_tid=All&amp;page=0%2C0%2C1">https://aldeiasdoxisto.pt/en/poi/</a></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Resiliência Exhibition - Art, Music, Poetry - 2019</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ponte d&#x27;Arte</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://pontedarte.org/resiliencia-exhibition-art-music-poetry-2019.html"/>
        <id>https://pontedarte.org/resiliencia-exhibition-art-music-poetry-2019.html</id>

        <updated>2019-09-23T12:15:02+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://pontedarte.org/media/posts/34/resiliencia_flyer_pontedarte11.jpg" alt="On 13 October 2019, we remember the &quot;Resiliência&quot; of living with wildfires in Portugal.  Join us at Ponte d&#x27;Arte, an artist-run organisation in Ponte Da Mucela, to listen to music, be transported by poetry, and experience art experiments. " />
                    Resiliência (Resilience)[EN] On October 13, 2019, we remember the "Resiliência" of living&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://pontedarte.org/media/posts/34/resiliencia_flyer_pontedarte11.jpg" alt="On 13 October 2019, we remember the &quot;Resiliência&quot; of living with wildfires in Portugal.  Join us at Ponte d&#x27;Arte, an artist-run organisation in Ponte Da Mucela, to listen to music, be transported by poetry, and experience art experiments. " />
                <h2 id="mcetoc_1dleprqeu1" class="p1">Resiliência (Resilience)</h2>
<p>[EN]  On October 13, 2019, we remember the "Resiliência" of living with the wildfires in Portugal.  Join us at Ponte d'Arte, an artist-run organization in Ponte da Mucela, to listen to music, be transported by poetry, and experience works of art.  Our exhibition will take place on October 13th between and 18h, at Rua Principal 143 (EN17), Ponte da Mucela.</p>
<p class="p3">In the disaster two years ago, in October 2017, due to fires aggravated by climate change and a hurricane, we suffered from the injuries and deaths of some people in our region.  We too have lost our possessions to this disaster, but have decided to continue.  We have rebuilt something bigger and better from the ashes in Ponte da Mucela, and our dream is to share it with all culture lovers.</p>
<p class="p3">Forest fires are an ancient and recurring problem in Portugal, and growing due to climate change.  We are motivated by the belief in the healing power of creativity to transform pain.  Our writer in residence, the multilingual Galician poet Alfredo J. Ferreiro Salgueiro, will present spoken poetry.  Together with some other artists, a group of art students will present their work on "resilence" from their participation in a site-specific art workshop.  These students will be mentored by Prof.  Kris van 't Hof and Caroline van den Eynden of the Royal Academy in Antwerp, Belgium, and Celia De Villiers, South African artist and lecturer.</p>
<p class="p3">We have a vision for a day and night of inspiration and remembering.  In this way, we invite the local community, the neighbors of the surrounding regions, as well as national and international academics, thinkers and artists to return to this house we are building to be dedicated to creative practice.  We hope to turn the fire tragedy into an annual event celebrating resilience through the arts, and perhaps in the future, even a music festival.</p>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1dlepol3a0" class="p1">Resiliência</h2>
<p>[PT]  No dia 13 de outubro de 2019, lembramos a "Resiliência" de viver com os incêndios em Portugal. Junte-se a nós na Ponte d'Arte, uma organização dirigida por artistas em Ponte da Mucela, para ouvir música, ser transportado por poesia e experimentar obras de arte. A nossa exposição irá decorrer no dia 13 de Outubro entre as 14h e as 18h, na Rua Principal 14 (EN17), Ponte da Mucela.</p>
<p class="p1"> No desastre de há dois anos, em outubro de 2017, devido aos incêndios agravados pelas alterações climáticas e por um furacão, sofremos com os ferimentos e as mortes de algumas pessoas na nossa região. Também nós perdemos as nossas posses para este desastre, mas decidimos continuar. Reconstruímos algo maior e melhor das cinzas em Ponte da Mucela, e o nosso sonho é compartilhá-lo com todos os amantes da cultura.</p>
<p class="p1">Os incêndios florestais são um problema antigo e recorrente em Portugal, e com um crescimento cada vez mais acentuado devido às alterações climáticas. Somos motivados pela crença no poder curativo da criatividade para transformar a dor. O nosso escritor em residência, o poeta galego multilíngue Alfredo J. Ferreiro Salgueiro, apresentará poesia recitada. Juntamente com alguns outros artistas, um grupo de estudantes de arte irá apresentar os seus trabalhos sobre "resilência" a partir da sua participação num workshop de arte <i>site-specific</i>. Estes estudantes terão como mentores o Prof. Kris van 't Hof e Caroline van den Eynden da Royal Academy em Antuérpia, Bélgica, e Celia De Villiers, artista sul-africana e conferencista.</p>
<p class="p1">Temos uma visão para um dia e uma noite de inspiração e de memória. Deste modo, convidamos a comunidade local, os vizinhos das regiões circundantes, assim como académicos, pensadores e artistas nacionais e internacionais a regressar a esta casa que estamos a construir para que seja dedicada à prática criativa. Esperamos transformar a tragédia do incêndio num evento anual comemorando a resiliência através das artes, e talvez no futuro, até de um Festival de Música.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Contact us</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ponte d&#x27;Arte</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://pontedarte.org/contact-us.html"/>
        <id>https://pontedarte.org/contact-us.html</id>

        <updated>2019-09-16T19:58:29+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://pontedarte.org/media/posts/33/P1050002.jpg" alt="" />
                     Thank you for your interest in Ponte d'Arte. We'd love to&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://pontedarte.org/media/posts/33/P1050002.jpg" alt="" />
                <blockquote>
<p> </p>
<p>Thank you for your interest in Ponte d'Arte.</p>
<p>We'd love to hear from you.<br><br>Regards,</p>
<p><a href="https://pontedarte.org/kris-van-t-hof.html">Kris</a> &amp; <a href="https://pontedarte.org/celia-de-villiers.html">Celia</a></p>
<p> </p>
</blockquote>
<table border="0" width="100%">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td width="20%"> </td>
<td width="60%">
<h2 id="mcetoc_1dktj1pb42">Your message</h2>
</td>
<td width="20%"> </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td bgcolor="white"> </td>
<td bgcolor="olive" width="60%"><form action="https://formspree.io/pontedarte.artsbridge@gmail.com" method="POST">
<p><input name="email" type="email" placeholder="Your email"></p>
<p><textarea cols="40" name="message" rows="10" placeholder="Message"></textarea></p>
<p><button type="submit">SEND</button></p>
</form></td>
<td bgcolor="white">
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Events</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ponte d&#x27;Arte</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://pontedarte.org/events-and-gatherings.html"/>
        <id>https://pontedarte.org/events-and-gatherings.html</id>

        <updated>2019-09-17T23:23:05+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://pontedarte.org/media/posts/32/2019-Instagram-pontedarte-Aug123.jpg" alt="" />
                    The complex is currently undergoing conversion to become a meeting centre with&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://pontedarte.org/media/posts/32/2019-Instagram-pontedarte-Aug123.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>The complex is currently undergoing conversion to become a meeting centre with large and small exhibition spaces, 300m<sup>2</sup> gallery/concert hall, video rooms, a conference room, an art library, studios and workshops, and a small local museum. </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Shared accommodation</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ponte d&#x27;Arte</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://pontedarte.org/shared-accommodation.html"/>
        <id>https://pontedarte.org/shared-accommodation.html</id>

        <updated>2019-09-16T13:52:25+02:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Conimbriga</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ponte d&#x27;Arte</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://pontedarte.org/conimbriga.html"/>
        <id>https://pontedarte.org/conimbriga.html</id>

        <updated>2019-09-16T18:44:23+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://pontedarte.org/media/posts/30/Conimbriga_calling_article.jpg" alt="" />
                    Conímbriga is one of the largest Roman settlements excavated in Portugal, and was classified as a National&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://pontedarte.org/media/posts/30/Conimbriga_calling_article.jpg" alt="" />
                <p><strong>Conímbriga</strong> is one of the largest <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roman_Empire" title="Roman Empire">Roman</a> settlements excavated in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Portugal" title="Portugal">Portugal</a>, and was classified as a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monuments_of_Portugal" class="mw-redirect" title="Monuments of Portugal">National Monument</a> in 1910. Located in the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Freguesia_(Portugal)" class="mw-redirect" title="Freguesia (Portugal)">civil parish</a> of Condeixa-a-Velha e Condeixa-a-Nova, in the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Concelho" title="Concelho">municipality</a> of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Condeixa-a-Nova" title="Condeixa-a-Nova">Condeixa-a-Nova</a>, it is situated 2 kilometres (1.2 mi) from the municipal seat and 16 kilometres (9.9 mi) from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coimbra" title="Coimbra">Coimbra</a> (the Roman town of <i><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aeminium" title="Aeminium">Aeminium</a></i>).</p>
<p>Conímbriga is a walled urban settlement, encircled by a curtain of stone structures approximately 1,500 metres (4,900 ft) long. Entrance to the settlement is made from vaulted structures consisting of two doors (one on hinges), and at one time was defended by two towers. The walls are paralleled by two passages, channelled to excavations, in order to remove water infiltration from the walls. The urban settlement consists of various structures such as a forum, basilica and commercial shops, thermal spas, aqueducts, insulae, homes of various heights (including interior patios) and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domus" title="Domus">domus</a> (such as the <i>Casa dos Repuxos</i> and <i>Casa de Cantaber</i>), in addition to paleo-Christian basilica.</p>
<p>A visitors' centre (which includes restaurant/café and gift-shop) was constructed to display objects found by archaeologists during their excavations, including coins, surgical tools, utensils and ceramics.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Bussaco Palace</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ponte d&#x27;Arte</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://pontedarte.org/bussaco-palace.html"/>
        <id>https://pontedarte.org/bussaco-palace.html</id>

        <updated>2019-09-16T18:48:52+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://pontedarte.org/media/posts/29/1280px-Palacio_Hotel_de_Bussaco_XL.jpg" alt="Bussaco Palace / Palácio Hotel do Buçaco" />
                    History The Bussaco Palace was built between 1888 and 1907.The palace, commissioned by&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://pontedarte.org/media/posts/29/1280px-Palacio_Hotel_de_Bussaco_XL.jpg" alt="Bussaco Palace / Palácio Hotel do Buçaco" />
                <div id="block-dexp-page-elements-dexp-page-elements-page-title" class="block block-dexp-page-elements">
<div class="content">
<div class="page_title_no_sub">
<h2 id="mcetoc_1dktfhua00" class="page_title">History</h2>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div id="block-views-hotel-block" class="block block-views">
<div class="inner"> </div>
<div class="inner">The Bussaco Palace was built between 1888 and 1907.</div>
<div class="content">
<div class="view view-hotel view-id-hotel view-display-id-block Hotel view-dom-id-e8dd7ade732ed5a92e96c1872f6bb565">
<div class="view-content">
<div class="views-row views-row-1 views-row-odd views-row-first views-row-last">
<div>
<div class="text">
<p>The palace, commissioned by King Charles I of Portugal as a royal retreat, embodies the contemporaneous architectural fashion known as castle romanticism ( German: Burgenromantik) and all the national enthusiasm for the Age of the Discoveries.</p>
<p>By late 19th century, many castles were picturesquely constructed and abandoned castles were transformed into historic palaces - Neuschwanstein Castle, Lichtenstein Castle, Hohenzollern Castle, Stolzenfels Castle, Wartburg Castle and the Château de Pierrefonds are major examples of this trend. Charles, Ferdinand of Saxe-Coburg Gotha’s grandson, was naturally influenced by this ideal.</p>
<p>Initial ideas for the palace drew stylistically on a Falkenstein Castle, Ludwig II of Bavaria’s project that never left planning stages, to be built on the western slope of the hill, by the Coimbra Gates, but were quickly replaced by increasingly extensive drafts culminating in a Neo-Manueline style palace, modeled on the Belém Tower of Lisbon, the major symbol of the Portuguese Discoveries. Also the projected location was transferred to the site of the convent, so that part of it could be transformed into the new palace, matching the romantic ideal of a knight’s castle, hidden from view by dense, skyscraping trees. The young King’s romantic vision of a picturesque new Belém Tower amidst a tranquil green botanic ocean had to be fulfilled …</p>
<p>The building design was drafted by the Italian architect and National Opera House stage designer Luigi Manini, brought to Portugal by Queen Maria Pia of Savoy, Charles’s mother, and daughter of Victor Emmanuel II of Italy. He drafted a Romantic palace in Neo-Manueline gothic style, evoking the 16th-century architectural style that characterized the peak of the Portuguese Age of Discovery.</p>
<p>Manini was succeeded by architects Nicola Bigaglia, José Alexandre Soares and Manuel Joaquim Norte Júnior, the latter responsible for the annex “Casa dos Brasões” (House of the Coat-of-Arms), and also for the extraordinary Curia Palace and for the renowned “Café a Brasileira”, in Lisbon.</p>
<p>The inner rooms are richly decorated with Neo-Manueline portals and stucco work imitating Manueline rib vaulting, being also an important showcase of Portuguese painting and sculpture of the early 20th century. The inner walls are also decorated with tile (azulejos) panels by Jorge Colaço. These panels depict scenes taken from Portuguese literature as well as historical events like the Battle of Bussaco.</p>
<p>In 1885 - exactly one year after Ludwig II moved to the still unfinished Neuschwanstein Castle - the dining hall , the kitchen, the library and some cells of the convent were demolished and the foundation stone was laid.</p>
<p>The palace was erected as a conventional brick construction and later encased with other types of rock, mainly limestone from a nearby quarry, sandstone from nearby Ançã, and marble from Vila Viçosa, in the Alentejo. The forest also provided essential conifers, oak, and chestnut premium quality woods.</p>
<p>For about 25 years the construction site was the principal employer of the region and of all major Portuguese artists of the period.</p>
<p>The palace consists of several individual structures, and the main building – a flurry of excesses and a hotchpotch of styles - is furnished with a rectangular tower overlooking the Atlantic coastline, ornamental turrets, gables and gargoyles, balconies, pinnacles, arches and sculptures.</p>
<p>Following Romanesque style, some windows openings are fashioned as bi- and triforia.</p>
<p>Unlike “real” castles, Bussaco Palace was planned from the inception as an intentionally asymmetric building, and erected in consecutive stages. Typical attributes of a castle were included, but real fortifications – the most important feature of a medieval aristocratic estate – were dispensed with.</p>
<p>Today the palace is a fully functioning luxury hotel, and can be visited as part of a tour of the Bussaco complex.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Celia de Villiers</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ponte d&#x27;Arte</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://pontedarte.org/celia-de-villiers.html"/>
        <id>https://pontedarte.org/celia-de-villiers.html</id>

        <updated>2019-09-18T09:35:10+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://pontedarte.org/media/posts/28/celia.jpg" alt="" />
                    BiographyCelia de Villiers has three tertiary qualifications, including a MA in Visual&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://pontedarte.org/media/posts/28/celia.jpg" alt="" />
                <h3 id="mcetoc_1dkb61pgh0">Biography</h3>
<p>Celia de Villiers has three tertiary qualifications, including a MA in Visual Arts (cum laude). A fellow of the the Sacatar foundation of California, she has also been credited by the World Craft Council, and endorsed by UNESCO. She has exhibited, curated and adjudicated extensively in South Africa and abroad, as well as presented and published academic articles in South Africa, the United States, Brazil, Romania, Belgium and France.</p>
<p>Her two and three-dimensional artworks in various media are held in corporate, museum and private collections such as the Raiffeisen Bank, Germany, Landesbank, Germany, Le Tousserok Sun International Hotel, Mauritius, UNISA, EnviroServ and the Development Bank, South Africa, Michigan State University, and the Museum of Art and Design, New York.</p>
<p>The artist has facilitated and consulted for community outreach and social art initiatives for eighteen years, and won government awards for job creation in the arts and crafts sector in South Africa. She has served on the board of the UNISA gallery, the EnviroServ WasteArt Foundation, the SA government department of Arts and Culture, and the SA Bureau of Standards for Craft.</p>
<p>De Villiers has lectured in Drawing, Painting, Sculpture, Conceptualisation and Art theory from first to postgraduate level at the University of South Africa, The Design School of South Africa and the University of Pretoria between 2001 to 2018, as well as presenting workshops internationally.</p>
<p>She relocated from South Africa to Europe in 2015, where she spends her time between Belgium and Portugal. Most recently she has been a guest lecturer at the Royal Academy of Art in Antwerp (2015 -2018), engaged in a European Union funded project between universities in Dublin, Ireland, Turku, Finland and Zagreb, Croatia (2016 - 2018).</p>
<p>She is a co-director of Ponte d’ Arte, an Artistic Hub and Residency near Coimbra, Portugal, whilst remaining a passionate crafter and artist.</p>
<p>See her work at <a href="http://www.celiadevilliers.com">http://www.celiadevilliers.com</a>.</p>
<p>Celia joins Kris as artist mentor on his popular <a href="https://pontedarte.org/master-classes.html">In Situ3 Master Classes</a><strong>.</strong></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
